(This story is entirely fictional)
Before Le Tianyi died, he said
that he didn't kill Wen.
(Based on the novel
Doctor Qin: Executer)
He was lying.
I saw it with my own eyes.
Why didn't you call the cops back then?
I was scared.
I was afraid they'd leak the videos.
Then I'd be completely ruined.
Don't be scared.
Mom's here.
As long as I'm around...
nobody gets away.
(Jin Keke saw Le Tianyi kill Wen)
(with her own eyes.)
(But what if Le Tianyi wasn't lying?)
(What if the real killer
is still alive?)
(Then what did you actually see?)
(Is it a memory you made up)
(to keep yourself going?)
(Or were you lying all along?)
=Doctor Qin: Executer=
=Episode 26=
The drone footage the police have
was deliberately left behind
by Ms. Song.
She must have started
suspecting you back then.
We found out Song Yalan worked
as an engineer
at Longfan Shengxing Chemical Plant
for five years
before she became a teacher.
Mainly responsible
for chemical formulation.
(Her resignation file says
she left the company)
(to switch to education.)
(Her suitcase)
(is full of books
on explosive principles)
(and mechanical manufacturing.)
We searched the abandoned water tower
and found blueprints
for rocket launchers
and homemade guns
designed by Song Yalan.
She poured hours
into grinding through all this stuff,
hand you these tools
for revenge.
Put it on.
Then you, Wen, and I
will truly be connected.
Wen can feel
your heartbeat.
I can feel your determination.
If one day
you waver or get scared,
just touch it.
Think about how Wen looked
when she died.
Think about how good Wen was to you.
She finally had a home
and a mom.
Even if that mom was stolen,
she refused to let go
of that gentle rope.
(Middle School)
(Jin Keke!)
♪Sunset washes over the old wall♪
(Qin Ming!)
♪Unspoken words just flee and fade♪
♪The marks on the desk
have faded yellow♪
Leave the soda before you go.
♪No one can truly feel another's pain♪
♪The wind is cold,
a fading shadow sways♪
You seem to like coming to the rooftop.
You're following me?
No.
I just
happen to like rooftops too.
Why?
If you think of the human eye
as a camera,
when we read books,
look at test papers or the blackboard,
everything in our eyes
is a medium close-up or a close-up.
The field of view is narrow.
But once you get to the rooftop,
the view suddenly opens up.
The eye's wide-angle mode turns on,
and the world suddenly feels bigger.
Sounds like a camera manual.
But I get it.
Standing here,
you feel the sun
is close enough to touch.
But it's 150 million kilometers away
from us.
All we see every day
is just a beam of light
that took eight minutes to get here.
Most of what people believe in
their whole lives
is this kind of illusion.
You think it's close enough,
but it's actually far away.
Hey, what are you doing?
We...
What class are you in?
What's your name?
Can't you see that huge seal?
No going up to the rooftop!
Get down here!
(Class 2, Senior 3)
(In an ethylene molecule,
the carbon and hydrogen atoms)
(all lie in the same plane.)
(If each double-bonded carbon atom)
(in an ethylene molecule)
(is connected to two different atoms)
(or atomic groups...)
(Qin Ming.)
Qin Ming.
You're late again.
(Location)
Qin Ming,
the fact that you're standing here
means you actually went
through the homework
I left you.
Ms. Song.
It's time to end this.
No. It's time for class.
(The Last Lesson)
Sit down.
Song Yalan's location is locked.
Let's go!
Got it!
One of a teacher's duties
is to answer her students' questions.
Go ahead and ask.
Your answer
for Le Tianyi's death
wasn't the right one.
Impressive.
As expected of you, Qin Ming.
So what's your answer?
You couldn't have turned Le Tianyi
into pig feed all by yourself.
But both Jin Keke and Wang Xuan
had alibis that day.
Then who do you think it was?
I think
that person is already dead.
Who are you?
I didn't kill her.
Really, it wasn't me.
Mr. Zhang.
Zhang Xiaodong!
It's him!
He told me to kill your daughter!
You killed my daughter!
Uncle Le.
Tianyi,
she doesn't seem dead yet.
Still breathing.
Uncle Le.
She's dead.
I said she's dead. Did you hear me?
Uncle Le.
Yeah, she's dead.
Dead.
Bury.
Hurry up!
Move faster!
Forgot to tell you.
Zhang Xiaoya was buried alive
by Le Tianyi.
Mr. Zhang.
Mr. Zhang?
Xiaoya,
I've avenged you.
Go ahead and ask.
Who
killed Zhang Xiaodong?
Didn't Zhang Xiaodong tell you?
Dr. Qin,
isn't it said that corpses talk?
Our autopsy results show
Zhang Xiaodong drowned.
Drowned? So he killed himself!
Ms. Song.
That's just playing with words.
Isn't playing games exactly
what you love, Zhang Xiaodong?
I'll stab you all I want!
Why won't you leave her alone?
Why couldn't you just let her go?
She was only seventeen.
Why did you...?
Mr. Zhang,
you like watching your prey struggle,
don't you?
I'm gonna kill you.
I'll kill you!
The water's full of your pets.
They love the blood of animals.
But he forgot
that collectibles can resent the master
who stares at them.
Now, it's his turn
to be the prey on display.
In that cold, dark swamp,
his prized cold-bloodedness and greed
look so pathetic and weak
in front of
his true kind.
Qin Ming,
the more you struggle,
the more this poison hurts.
If you want to live,
finish the last lesson
like a good student.
Listen.
The sound of bones being torn apart
(The Last Lesson)
is his finest tribute as a collectible!
Have you ever thought
about how you're any different
from those scumbags
like Zhang Xiaodong?
You destroyed yourself,
and you destroyed Jin Keke.
She saw you as a mother,
but you turned killing people
into her way of repaying you,
making her commit monstrous crimes!
You're more terrifying
than that demon Zhang Xiaodong.
He only wanted to destroy
people's bodies.
But you destroy people's souls.
Now it's my turn to ask you.
Do you know
why you're the one here today
for the last lesson?
(Keke!)
At first, I thought
she just wanted to run a test
to see how much you valued her.
But later I realized
she wanted to tell us a truth
before her death.
You
saved her.
I
was going to forgive her.
But now I can't.
Ms. Song,
you had the lawyer pass
a message to her,
didn't you?
She's completely broken down.
She used to see you
as her last emotional anchor.
(Mom, I miss you. I miss you.)
Why did you have to be so cruel?
Cruel?
Qin Ming,
you're calling me cruel?
Fine.
Let me tell you why!
I wanted her to feel
the most extreme despair!
Not fear. Not pain.
(The Last Lesson)
It's that despair
of being pushed off a cliff!
Just like what Wen went through!
(Qin.)
(Jin Keke just killed herself
at the hospital.)
♪Sunset washes over the old wall♪
♪Milk tea cools on the stone steps♪
♪Sea wind tugs at your sleeve♪
♪Unspoken words just flee and fade♪
♪The marks on the desk
have faded yellow♪
♪I turned around,
and a gunshot rang out♪
♪No one can truly feel another's pain♪
♪The wind is cold,
a fading shadow sways♪
♪Tonight, I don't care
about the universe♪
♪I only want to see this through
with you♪
♪A bullet pierces the spring night♪
♪You sink into the vast crowd♪
♪Years later, when we meet again♪
♪Don't mention this moonlit night♪
♪The waves smooth
two lines of footprints♪
♪Half a cup of sweetness
sinks into the sand♪
♪Tonight, I don't care
about the universe♪
♪I only want to see this through
with you♪
♪Wind back to shore,
clouds back to hills♪
♪We stop here in this night♪
♪This is the past, the only,
the last look back♪
♪One gunshot echoes through half a life♪